<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Disasters | You Are Curio.us]]></title>
  <link href="http://YouAreCurious.github.io/categories/disasters/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://YouAreCurious.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-17T15:07:30+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://YouAreCurious.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Pubudu Kodikara]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deepwater Horizon Oil Spill : Human Error? What Can We Learn From it? [Documentary]]]></title>
    <link href="http://YouAreCurious.github.io/2013/05/deepwater-horizon-oil-spill/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-05T22:53:40+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://YouAreCurious.github.io/2013/05/deepwater-horizon-oil-spill</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/post-images/2013/05/deep-water-horizon.jpg" title="Deepwater Horizon Oil Spill" alt="Deepwater Horizon Oil Spill" /></p>

<p>Most of you might already know about the Deepwater Horizon Oil Spill that shook the Gulf of Mexico. A series of human error have led to the destruction of the drilling rig with 11 lives. It didn&rsquo;t stop there&hellip; The crippled pipeline have discharged 4.9 million barrels of oil into the sea covering an area of 180,000 km2. The impact on the environment and on the health of coastal residents are huge. The damage is irreversible! Now we are going to look at what happened at the Deepwater Horizon Oil Spill&hellip; What can we learn from it?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>First, watch this video and learn what happened, then we can discuss :</p>

<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/V9QCmA-sxmQ?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p><sub>This video belongs to <a href="http://natgeotv.com/uk/seconds-from-disaster/videos/deepwater-horizon">National Geographic Channel</a>. If you like it, please buy the series. </sub></p>

<h3></h3>

<h3>What can we learn from the Deepwater Horizon Oil Spill?</h3>

<p>According to National Geographic, the Deepwater Horizon Oil Spill is caused by human error! Deepwater Horizon is an oil drilling rig. It will drill holes leading to oil deposits. Then another rig will come and extract it. BP have leased this rig owned by Transocean to dig the deepest oil well in history. Already they were behind the schedule by nearly 40 days. So, they were in a hurry. It cost millions of dollars to run the rig for one day. So, they need to find a cheap way to finish the drill. Cost problems and Speed problems&hellip; The perfect recipe that can dissolve Safety! Deepwater Horizon Oil Spill is inevitable!</p>

<h3>They were in a hurry&hellip; They thought about money&hellip; Never do that!</h3>

<p>The operation have met some delays and now they are nearly 40 days behind the original schedule. That&rsquo;s a lot of time&hellip; They should have faced an immense pressure from the high officials to complete the job in time. If it&rsquo;s a job which doesn&rsquo;t have high safety threats, then its ok to apply pressure on the crew and get the job done in time. But now they are in the middle of the ocean&hellip; Drilling an oil well nearly 35,050 feet (nearly 10.6 kilometers) deep&hellip; Oil is highly flammable&hellip; They are sitting in a ticking time bomb. It can go off at any moment! At a time like this, safety should be the first priority. But, they risked their own safety to do the job fast and save some money!</p>

<p>Ask from yourself before taking such risks&hellip; Do you think money is more important than your life? The crew didn&rsquo;t understand this. So, 11 people had to pay with their lives. In a high risk situation like this, you should never ignore key safety measures. These people did it four times. They used a low quality cement to plug the well&hellip; They used only 6 centralizes instead of 21 because getting the extra 15 will eat more time&hellip; They didn&rsquo;t fix a flaw in the blow out preventer&hellip; They ignored the pressure readings to save time&hellip; The Deepwater Horizon Oil Spill is inevitable!</p>

<p>This is not the first occasion where time and money have brought disaster. Most of the plane crashes in the world occur due to these issues. That&rsquo;s an industry where safety is the top priority. But to save time and money, some pilots find shortcuts, some air lines find shortcuts for maintenance which leads to disaster! You should ever do that!</p>

<h3>The decision makers were not at the field&hellip; They only thought about money&hellip;</h3>

<p>Some of the decisions that triggered the Deepwater Horizon Oil Spill were made by people several hundred kilometers away from the rig. They don&rsquo;t care about the safety because they are in a safe distant. They don&rsquo;t feel the full weight of the issues. While BP engineers recommended to use 21 centralizes, one of the BP&rsquo;s team leaders have ordered the crew to go with 6 because of time and money. How can they think about their time and money and risk some one else&rsquo;s life?</p>

<p>The crew at the rig refused to use the low quality cement. But BP, after using a partially complete test result ordered to use the low quality cement. The Deepwater Horizon Oil Spill is inevitable!</p>

<h3>Poor communication&hellip; The decision makers should know everything!</h3>

<p>BP gave the OK to use the low quality cement after the cementer Halliburton gave a partially complete report on the cement quality. They conducted several tests to determine whether the mix used in the rig can do the job. Only one test have passed while the others failed. But Halliburton gave only the report of the passed test to BP. Why didn&rsquo;t they gave all the reports? According to them, BP haven&rsquo;t told them about the exact situation in the rig.</p>

<p>If you are facing a critical situation like this, you should always open your mouth and give all the information to the decision makers. The decision makers should know every detail. Otherwise, they will make wrong decisions!</p>

<p>Time, Money, Poor selfish decisions and poor communication have curved the path to the Deepwater Horizon Oil Spill. Ironically, the Deepwater Horizon rig had an excellent safety record. It took only several days to shatter its reputation!</p>

<p><strong>We fight a lot to earn money&hellip; We try to earn millions&hellip; Some people have several cars. But you can go only in one car at a time. We earn a lot&hellip; Think&hellip; What are our main goals? To eat and drink&hellip; Simply to stay alive! Why do we need millions to do it? Even though we earn a lot, there&rsquo;s a limit where we can spend them. But your life is invaluable. So, think twice before putting your or other&rsquo;s lives in risk for money!</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
