<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: History | You Are Curio.us]]></title>
  <link href="http://YouAreCurious.github.io/categories/history/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://YouAreCurious.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-17T15:07:30+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://YouAreCurious.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Pubudu Kodikara]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things You Don't Know About Hitler]]></title>
    <link href="http://YouAreCurious.github.io/2013/06/hitler/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-18T20:59:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://YouAreCurious.github.io/2013/06/hitler</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/post-images/2013/06/hitler.jpg" title="Hitler" alt="Hitler" /></p>

<p>Before starting to study history, I knew very little about Hitler. I knew him as the vicious savage man who killed millions of people! Why did he started the war? Is it just because he is mad? He said he and the other pure Germans are the most superior race on this planet! Is it true? Lets find out&hellip;</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Hitler is not a German and his race is unknown!</h3>

<p>This will be a real blow to most of you. Yes&hellip; Its true&hellip; Hitler is not a German! He was born in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Austria">Austria</a>. Very close to the German border. Hitler killed because of a racial problem. He wanted to eliminate the Jews. But Hitler&rsquo;s own race is unknown. No one know whether he belong to a good race or to Jews. It was a very closely guarded secret!</p>

<h3>Why did he started the war?</h3>

<p>First, Hitler was just a courier for the German army. During the 1<sup>st</sup> World War, he saw the carnage first hand. The Allies hit Germany very hard. In this hard time, the Jews have refused to help them! The role played by the Jews is a bit unclear at this moment. Some say they were innocent and some say they are the cause. People say that, because Jews doesn&rsquo;t have their own country, they lived in other nations. But they were not patriotic. They never help the country they live in. If you check the history, many wars started due to these Jews. Its still unclear to me why they are so hated. Hitler also hated them for not supporting his country. So he thought of getting rid of them!</p>

<p>After the World War I, the Allies enforced harsh rules against Germany. The country became one of the poorest nations on earth. Hitler wanted to change this. World War I completely changed him. Actually, the World War I created Hitler! If the records are correct, he fought for his own people! To save his own nation. But he did it the wrong way.</p>

<h3>Hitler called himself an Aryan!</h3>

<p>Hitler said he belongs to the Aryan race. But the truth is, Aryans lived in India. Its a noble pure race. Lord Buddha is an Aryan. Lord Buddha later called people who follow his religion are Aryans. Not as a race, just a name. (But the Buddha completely denied the races. He told us that everyone is equal.). But now we know that even Hitler didn&rsquo;t knew his real race!</p>

<h3>Hitler said he and his followers belong to a superior race! Are they that superior?</h3>

<p>In here we should first note that before Hitler, Germany was a poor country which had a very small military force. Most of its military powers were removed after the 1<sup>st</sup> World War. Hitler somehow made this nation into one of the most powerful nations on earth! He did bring glory for his own people. Many mainstream technologies that we use today were invented by Hitler&rsquo;s scientists. His scientists invented the first jet engine. His scientists invented the first ballistic missile. His scientists cracked the secrets of nuclear energy! They are genius!</p>

<p>Hitler did a lot of stuff for his nation. But still, he did it in the wrong way. He killed millions of people without any hesitation. He was a brutal killer. The whole world know that. But I don&rsquo;t think most of you knew the stuff I talked today. There are more secrets in his life which need to be uncovered. I will surely let you know when I learn more about him. So, <a href="http://eepurl.com/yH0mv">stay in touch</a>!</p>

<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/3hEG-5_9nK4?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<br>


<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/cqPc93Pvs0U?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Did Our Ancient People Used Electricity? Here's What I Think...]]></title>
    <link href="http://YouAreCurious.github.io/2013/05/ancient-people-used-electricity/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-01T18:10:34+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://YouAreCurious.github.io/2013/05/ancient-people-used-electricity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/post-images/2013/05/ancient-people-used-electricity.jpg" title="Ancient People Used Electricity?" alt="Ancient People Used Electricity?" /></p>

<p>We already know that our ancestors constructed great monuments that make us think &ldquo;How on earth did they do that?&rdquo;! How did they build massive structures like the great pyramid? How did they move large stones like the 800 ton <a href="http://atheism.about.com/od/religiousplaces/ig/Baalbek-Temples-Lebanon/Baalbek-Trilithon-Stone-Blocks.htm">Baalbek Trilithon</a> in Lebanon? How did they carve stones in high precision without a single crack? Did they had Alien help or did they used their own knowledge? Did our ancient people used electricity?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Lets take the Pyramids first. Some say these Pyramids were built long before the Egyptians for a different purpose. We can&rsquo;t prove this theory. We also don&rsquo;t have enough facts to deny this theory. We can&rsquo;t carbon date the Pyramids because they were built with stones. Archaeologists carbon date the mummies or other pieces within the stones that can be dated. But what if they were from repairs done to an existing structure? Normally, Pyramids contain hieroglyphs&hellip; Drawings made by the Egyptians to tell the story of the Pharaoh. But the archaeologists failed to find any drawing or inscription inside the great Pyramid of Giza. People believe it was built for the pharaoh named Kufu. Many Pyramids have been robbed by tomb robbers. But archaeologists found the great Pyramid intact. That mean they should have discovered a lot of artifacts and the mummy of Kufu. But surprisingly, they didn&rsquo;t find any mummy inside the Pyramid! Then why did the Egyptians build it?</p>

<p>In Baghdad Iraq, archaeologists have discovered an ancient battery. They call it the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baghdad_Battery">Baghdad Battery</a>. They are terracotta pots containing a copper cylinder. Inside the copper cylinder, they found an iron rod. Some scientists say it can be a battery but some say its not. Still, there&rsquo;s no way to prove both the theories.</p>

<p>If the battery theory is correct, then we can say that our ancient people used electricity. Based on this theory, some people think the great Pyramid have been used as a power plant. According to the way the structure is built, the ancient astronaut theorists believe it can be used to generate electricity and distribute it through out the world using microwave energy! The theory is a bit far-fetched and hard to believe. But, check this video before continuing :</p>

<iframe src="http://www.disclose.tv/embed/120371" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p><sub>&ndash; If you liked the video, you can buy the whole series from the <a href="http://shop.history.com/ancient-aliens/index.php?v=history_show_ancient-aliens">History Channel</a></sub></p>

<p><em>Before continuing, we need to clarify one thing in this video&hellip; They have mentioned about the mount Kailash as the birth place of Buddhism. I&rsquo;m a Buddhist and I have studied my religion well. I have never heard about this mountain. In pure Buddhism, there&rsquo;s no mention about that mountain!</em></p>

<p>Can you really believe the facts in that video? Did our ancient people used electricity? The Alien stuff can be hard to believe but what about the rest? The fact that our Ancient people used electricity and possessed technology to build these great monuments? Can we believe it? Still its hard because no one can prove them. Like our previous issues, in here also no one can prove them wrong.</p>

<p>However, we should know one thing&hellip; Our Ancestors were intelligent than us. We are less intelligent. What we have is knowledge. We take knowledge from the books and try to work according to them. But our ancestors thought clearly without any distractions. So, they were able to achieve great things. So, the fact that our ancient people used electricity can be true.</p>

<p>There are Aliens. It&rsquo;s selfish to think that we are all alone in this big universe. We are trying to find living beings like us. Who breathe oxygen and drink water&hellip; But can there be beings who breathe carbon dioxide and drink lava? Can be! In Earth, scientists are now discovering living beings in most extreme conditions. So, the fact that the aliens gave us the technology can be true. But don&rsquo;t bet on it too much!</p>

<h3>So, Did our ancient people used electricity?</h3>

<p>No matter what theory is right, still we can&rsquo;t understand how our ancient people lived. Did our ancient people used electricity? We don&rsquo;t know! Did they contact aliens? We don&rsquo;t know! We simply don&rsquo;t know&hellip; What we know is, they did great things that we still can&rsquo;t!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yamato : The Largest Battleship Ever Built : Why Did it Fail? (Video)]]></title>
    <link href="http://YouAreCurious.github.io/2013/04/yamato-largest-battleship/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-29T15:31:48+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://YouAreCurious.github.io/2013/04/yamato-largest-battleship</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/post-images/2013/04/yamato.jpg" title="Yamato" alt="Yamato" /></p>

<p>During the World War II, Japan launched a project to build the largest battle ship on earth! The project was top-secret. Even its designers didn&rsquo;t knew they are building the largest battle ship ever built. They also launched the ship in secret. In Yamato, they installed the most powerful weapons including large 18.1 inch main guns. It can shoot down ships even before they can come close enough to shoot back. So, why did it fail?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Do you know why I call it a &ldquo;Fail&rdquo;? Even the greatest ship can sink. Many great and useful ships have been taken down during the war. Most of them can&rsquo;t be called failures. But the problem with Yamato is, the Japanese navy never used it to take down ships. The thing it&rsquo;s designed for. It only acted as the flagship of the fleet. As a command vessel  It was launched only about a handful of times. Most of the times, it  was docked. The crew have named it the &ldquo;Hotel Yamato&rdquo;. The food is good, the place is good, they barely worked&hellip; It&rsquo;s a real hotel!</p>

<h3>Why didn&rsquo;t they use Yamato in battle?</h3>

<p>Why didn&rsquo;t the Japanese Navy used their most powerful battle ship during the war? The real truth is, Yamato is not practical. At that time, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aircraft_carriers">Aircraft Carriers</a> have become the super powers in sea. Japan know this very well. They used their fleet of carriers to attack the Pearl Harbor. But still, they laid plans for Yamato after about a week after this battle. They might have planned it even before the Pearl Harbor mission. If that mission worked according to the plans, Yamato might have ruled the sea. But the Pearl Harbor attack didn&rsquo;t went as they expected. They planed to take down the US aircraft carriers. But none were there during the attack!</p>

<p>In April 1945, when the US fleet closed in on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_Okinawa">Okinawa</a>, Japan launched one desperate mission. They launched the Yamato and nine other battle ships to intercept the US fleet. Sadly, the US aircrafts took down Yamato easily. Its big. The largest battle ship&hellip; But the enemy possessed superior and practical weapons and tactics to match the ongoing war. So, Yamato sank with nearly 2,400 people on board!</p>

<h3>Lessons to learn from Yamato :</h3>

<p>The bigger they are, the harder they fall! We can learn a lot from Yamato. If you want a vehicle just for you to travel to your office, will you go for the biggest vehicle? Will you go for a big truck? A container? Will it be practical? It will be slow, hard to navigate through the traffic, hard to park! Will you go for it? Or will you go for a car? Think!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
